Finding Aid for International Order of King's Daughters and Sons. Macomb County Branch (Mich.) records, 1891-1965
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
International Order of King's Daughters and Sons. Macomb County Branch (Mich.) records 1891-1965
International Order of King's Daughters and Sons. Macomb County Branch (Mich.).
1.4 linear feet
89207 Bk.w 2
Minutes, financial records, annual convention reports, and scrapbooks, primarily of the Whatsoever Circle of Mount Clemens, Michigan.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Donated by the Macomb County Historical Society (Donor No. 7610 ) on October 27, 1988.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The International Order of the King's Daughters and Sons was founded in New York in 1886. It started as groups of Christian women from various churches came together to work and demonstrate their compassion for God and man. The Order was founded in small circles of ten, each adopting a symbol or motto for their name.
The Macomb County Branch was formed in 1891, and adopted the name, The Whatsoever Circle. This name was based on the saying, "Whatsoever thy hand findeth to do, do it with thy might." Other circles quickly grew and adopted such names as The Watchful Circle, United Workers, and Hand in Hand. The Circles involved themselves in Samaritan work, raising money for charities. The Whatsoever Circle actively supported the University of Michigan Hospitals among its many causes. Hand made goods as well as purchased items were donated in addition to time.
The various circles were administered locally by the City Union of The King's Daughters and Sons. The local groups were overseen by a state branch and finally the International Order. Annual yearly meetings were held for the county and state levels.
The records of the Macomb County Branch are made up of minutes documenting the activities and finances. The Whatsoever Circle is the best documented of the Mount Clemens Circles, running from the founding in 1891, through 1957. Other records include minutes from the City Union and The Board of Trustees. A scrapbook documents activities from 1901 through 1957, through clippings, brochures and letters.
Subjects:
Macomb County (Mich.); Mount Clemens (Mich.); Women--Michigan--Macomb County--Societies and clubs.
Genre Terms:
Scrapbooks.
- Minute book of The Whatsoever Circle (of King's Daughters and Sons), 1891-1957
  - 1891-1901 (Box 1)
  - 1901-1912 (Box 1)
  - 1912-1926 (Box 1)
  - 1927-1934 (Box 1)
  - 1935-1943 (Box 1)
  - 1944-1949 (Box 1)
  - 1953-1957 (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous records
  - Financial reports and minutes of the Whatsoever Circle, 1944-1953 (Box 1)
  - Minute book of the Mount Clemens Union of King's Daughters, 1901-1906 (Box 1)
  - Expenditure book, of The City Union of King's Daughters, 1906-1922 (Box 1)
  - Minute book of The City Union of the King's Daughters and Sons, 1911-1922 (Box 1)
  - Expense record, of The City Union of King's Daughters and Sons, 1924-1935 (Box 1)
  - Minute book of the King's Daughters and Sons Board of Trustees, 1923-1935 (Box 1)
  - Minute book, of The Watchful Circle, 1918-1923 (Box 1)
  - Minute book, of The Watchful Circle, 1923-1926 (Box 1)
  - Dues and membership book of The Watchful Circle, 1918-1926 (Box 1)
  - Constitutions and By-Laws of King's Daughters and Sons (Box 1)
  - Annual Convention reports of Macomb County Branch of the King's Daughters and Sons (Box 1)
  - Annual Convention reports of Michigan Branch of the King's Daughters and Sons (Box 1)
- Scrapbooks, The Whatsoever Circle of King's Daughters
  - 1901-1957 (Box 2)
  - 1934-1942 (Box 2)